Charles A. and June R. P. Ross Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Locality Information, Series I
  - Stratigraphic Sections., 002751
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - Stratigraphic sections (including field notes, stratigraphic columns and locality information) from C.A. Ross and printed notes from H.R. Wanless pertaining to C.A. Ross' 1973 publication in AAPG Bulletin; Section 17: Coolidge Dam section -- handwritten notes and stratigraphic column from C.A. Ross (samples 6-27-65-A, 9-3-66-D and E; notes from 9-3-66 and 3-19-68); Section 18: Gila Mountains section (6 mi NNE of Calva, AZ) -- handwritten notes and stratigraphic column (partial) from C.A. Ross (samples 9-3-66-A thru C); Section 25: Dos Cabezas -- handwritten stratigraphic notes (samples 7-13-65 O thru T); shared locality with Ross & Sabins (1965); Section 26: Dunn Spring Mountain section -- handwritten notes from C.A. Ross (on same sheet as sections 28 and 29; locality and stratigraphy notes only); Section 27: Blue Mountain -- 2 copies (1 handwritten, 1 copy) of a stratigraphic column (samples 8-26-66-A thru H); shared locality with Ross & Sabins (1965); Section 28:, 002762
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1967-2002 - Miscellaneous, Paleozoic stratigraphic columns, measured sections and section notes from Colorado and other western US states, measured by or re-drawn by C.A. Ross; reference lists for Paleozoic (Penn/Perm) sections from Texas, Nebraska, Alaska, California, Colorado and elsewhere; one field trip invitation detailing a trip to Chihuahua, Mexico [including Ojinaga, etc.] to visit Paleozoic strata; one interlibrary loan request from J.R.P. Ross for David Bostwick's 1958 Ph.D. thesis, titled "Stratigraphy of the (Pennsylvanian) Gaptank.", 003079
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Al Reed and Charles A. Ross - 1967 - Two stratigraphic sections from SE Arizona, including xeroxed copies of measured sections, handwritten stratigraphic notes, specimen IDs, associative sample numbers and specimen photography for the Coolidge Dam and Superior sections (measured by Al Reed)., 002778
    - Stratigraphic Sections. Charles A. Ross - 1983 - Copies of handdrawn stratigraphic sections and chronostratigraphic charts concerning Ordovician-Devonian strata in Nevada., 003180
- Miscellaneous, Series II
  - Correspondence., 002771
    - Correspondence & Dissertation Reviews. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Typewritten manuscript reviews of C.A. Ross' dissertation, titled "Type Wolfcamp series (Permian), Glass Mountains, Texas." C.A. Ross' committee members were Philip B. King (Chair), G.Arthur Cooper (Committee Member) and Raymond C. Douglass (Committee Member); one typewritten letter from Cooper to Ross covering updates of Cooper's Glass Mountains research and his acknowledgement of having shipped the worked-over copy of Ross' thesis (by King, Douglass and himself) back to Ross for edits; one photocopied version of a geologic map by C.A. Ross of Glass Mountains geology with red pencil notes., 003112
    - Correspondence and Research material. Charles A. Ross - 1961-1963 - Letters between C.A. Ross and various parties (1-7, exempting parties 8-9) pertaining to the continued investigation, status of fusulinid types and collections from Spitsbergen, Templefjord and Mt. Lykta, Norway; notes and specimen IDs by C.A. Ross on specimen photography taken from fusulinid collections from W.W. Hay (Collections 1-5, float from Spitsbergen and one collection from Mt. Lykta) and W.M. Furnish (Collections 1-4 from Spitsbergen). Attached to C.A. Ross' specimen IDs for the specimen photography is 3 pages of notes (by C.A. Ross) pertaining to three publications researched by Ross during his investigation of Spitsbergen; one stapled set of 10 3x5 index cards pertaining to specimen localities from Holtedahl; mounted prints of Text Figure 1 and plates 10-12 from Ross' 1965 publication on the Cyathophyllum Limestone, Spitsbergen, Svalbard, Norway., 002896
    - Correspondence and Research material. Charles A. Ross - 1962-1991 - Two Texas highway maps, one from 1962 (Scale ~1:1,900,000) and the other from 1987-1991 (Scale ~1:1,457,000). Not annotated with localities., 003160
    - Correspondence and Research material. Charles A. Ross - 1981-1984 - Internal correspondence, research material, progress reports, handdrawn and digital/analog copies of cross sections, chronostratigraphic charts, biozonation of Miss/Penn/Perm strata and Ord/Sil/Dev strata, locality maps with accompanying locality data, structure isopachs and reference lists relating to the Roberts Mountain Project, incepted by Gulf Oil Exploration and Production Company in 1981, and pursued through 1984. Correspondence includes 5 typed copies (3 complete, 2 partial) of Gulf Internal Correspondence (Oct. 11, 1982) sent by C.A. Ross to Roberts Mountain Field Project Participants, reporting the Sonoma GSA Penrose Conference; 1 typed letter from C.A. Ross to G. Steele (Gulf Internal Correspondence) discussing and showing (via sketch) tectonic and stratal relationships between Penn/Perm/Tri strata around Roberts Mountain; 1 typed letter, accompanied by four handdrawn sketches by C.A. Ross (sent to G. Steele) discussing tectonic and field, 003159
    - Correspondence and Research material. Charles A. Ross - 1982 - Internal correspondence containing a brief (2-page) discussion over fusulinid and foraminiferal picks for sections measured in and around the Congar Basin, Western Utah; this letter, to G. Steele, includes one copy of a handdrawn stratigraphic column of the Congar Basin Section (Mormon Gap quad., sec. 2 and 3, T25S, R19W, Millard County, Utah; Laurie A. Hietpas) with specimen IDs at stratigraphic heights and cycle (genetic?) picks at specific stratigraphic heights; this section covers primarily the Ely Group through Arcturus Grp (partial)., 003182
    - Correspondence and Research material. Charles A. Ross - 1984 - Photocopy of orrespondence between Jim Ellis and participants of the Roberts Mountains Project (Gulf Oil Exploration and Production Co.), addressing "fellow Nevada veterans" of the favorable status of the "Low-Sun-Angle" collection of toposheets and aerials housed at Gulf--Ellis invites participants to stop by Gulf to use its state-of-the-art zoom-stereoscope with calibrated photo holder and attached light table., 003183
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1958 - Two letters between C.A. Ross and G.A. Cooper--the first involves Cooper granting permission to Ross in utilizing specimens loaned to Carl O. Dunbar and suggestions in writing papers for the future (as well as his own). The second, written by Ross and sent to Cooper, requests locality details for some of Cooper's USNM Glass Mountains localities. and request for support in his submitting an AAPG research study proposal; handwritten lists of various USNM localities connecting C.A. Ross' collections with G.A. Cooper's USNM collections; one typewritten list detailing fusulinid identifications of specimens from some of Cooper's USNM localities., 003104
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1959 - One letter between C.A. Ross and J.R. Cooper regarding fusulinid specimens included within J.R. Cooper's PX-2 locality; specimen photography and locality information for fusulinids recovered from J.R. Cooper specimen collection PX-2., 002874
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - One letter between C.A. Ross and G.A. Cooper regarding the whereabouts of an Altuda quadrangle map containing annotated USNM localities within the Glass Mountains, West Texas; enclosed is a back page with three localties--duplicate lists for localities related to the ones from this letter are in IPARs 3098 and 3099 [see Associations Tab]., 003100
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - One letter from C.A. Ross to G.A. Cooper detailing Ross' return of samples and thin sections loaned to Ross by Cooper (sourced from the Leonard and Word formations) and comments related to some of Ross' findings from the loaned specimens., 003110
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and few parties (including K. Po?aryska of Polska Akademia Nauk and Franz Kirchheimer of the German Paleontological Society) discussing requests for microfilm of papers referencing Penn/Perm strata or fusulinids (K. Po?aryska), and to view fusulinid collections in Hannover, Germany (where Kirchheimer is located); one of Ross' business cards, with notes pertaining to "Mine M. Newmann" at the Saint-Jacques Laboratoire de Geologie appliquee; one letter from C.A. Ross to a person referred to as "Nils," offering thanks for train ride information and congratulations on curatorship of a Museum of Paleontology (located in Sweden or Norway), and asking for clarification on accommodations while staying in Oslo., 003131
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and T. Rocco discussing Ross' intention to visit the Stratigraphic Section of AGIP Mineraria, S. Donata Minanese - (MI), Italy to view Dr. Silvestri's fusulinid collections (typewritten), Ross' thanks for having been allowed to examine Silvestri's collections (Oct 6, 1960; handwritten draft), request and receipt for the book "Microfacies italiana" (published by AGIP Mineraria; letter is typewritten); one letter from E. Montanaro Gallitelli providing information on the whereabouts of Silvestri's collections (pre-dating Ross' correspondence with Rocco)., 003132
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and M.P. Mantovani discussing Ross' intention to visit the Stratigraphic Section of AGIP Mineraria, S. Donata Minanese - (MI), Italy to view Dr. Silvestri's fusulinid collections (typewritten), after having heard from E. Montanaro [see Associations Tab] that Silvestri's collections were not housed in Modena; Ross later sends a letter to Mantovani indicating his and June Ross' visit to her institute (AGIP Mineraria) September 1-2, 1960., 003133
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and R.H. Cummings; Ross praises Cummings' work on late Paleozoic foraminifera and requests audience with him and to see his collections during his upcoming visit to Glasgow, Scotland (Sept. 21-23, 1960); Cummings looks forward to their meeting in September and expresses thanks for Ross' kind words regarding his research., 003134
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and H. Hiltermann of Hannover, Germany pertaining to Ross' wishes to collect information on german institutions housing fusulinid collections; Hiltermann replies (in German), giving recommendations of a few individuals and institutions who may have collections housed, including Dr. Kahler and Dr. Kirchheimer (President at the German Paleontological Society) and his negative acknowledgment to the whereabouts of Wanner's Timor fusulinid collections., 003135
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and H.K. Erben; Ross' initial letter to Brinkman was deferred to Erben, who responded to Ross' inquiry into the whereabouts of fusulinid collections housed in the Geologisch-palaeontologisches Institut und Museum; Erben also notes their Wanner collection (Timor) doesn't include any fusulinids., 003137
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross & June R.P. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and C.L. Forbes, and J.R. Ross and O.M. Bulman, A.G. Brighton; both June and Charlie Ross ask Bulman and Forbes, respectively, to view the bryozoan and fusulinid collections of the Sedgewick Museum, Cambridge University, during both of the Ross' upcoming trip England September 14-20, 1960. Positive responses from Bulman, Brighton and Forbes in regards to access to these invertebrate collections, along with clarification as to exact days of September 1960 visitation, are discussed., 003140
    - Correspondence. June R.P. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between J.R. Ross and W. Krausel, detailing June's efforts towards setting up a meeting between C.A. Ross, Krausel and J.R. Ross to view Paleozoic fusulinid and bryozoa collections following the Ross' trip to Copenhagen (attending the international Geological Congress); June inquires the whereabouts of Wanner's fusulinid collections from Timor., 003146
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and A. Desio discussing plans to meet and have Ross examine the Paleozoic fusulinid collections housed at Desio's institution (Dept. of Geology, Universita Degli Studi, Milan, Italy); Ross wants to visit Milan, Italy on Sept. 1 but Desio requests to delay meeting plans until the second half of Sept., 003147
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and M. Reichel discussing meeting plans for August 30 to view the fusulinid collections housed at the University of Basel; Reichel is uncertain if he'll be in town that day, even though Ross finalizes his plans to be there (just in case)., 003148
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Two typewritten letters of correspondence between C.A. Ross and J. Roger of France; after Ross inquires to visit Roger's laboratory [sent to the "director"], Roger replies, giving thanks for Ross' previous letter, agreeing to meet during his visit to Paris and suggesting he contact Professor Ciry at the University of Dijon to discuss fusulinid collections housed there; he directs Ross towards collections housed at the Laboratoire de Geologie de la Sorbonne and at l'Ecole Nationale Superieure des Mines de Paris and states that Mr. Pierre Marie can show Ross around the micropaleolontological activities conducted by the Bureau Recherches Geologieque et Miniere; a card sent later (without a date) to Ross by J. Roger, and an undated, handwritten note to "the director" likely predating Ross' initial letter to Roger; one handwritten letter from C.A. Ross to Yolanda LeCalvey (working at the same Bureau as Roger), thanking her for hospitality during their visit to, 003150
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Two letters (typewritten) sent to Professor R. Ciry (University of Dijon, France) by C.A. Ross indicating Ross' interest in meeting at Ciry's geology lab to examine the fusulinid collections housed there; both letters, sent different dates, are nearly the same except for Ross' uncertainty, detailed in the second letter, hoping his first letter reached Ciry April 4., 003151
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Two letters (typewritten) between C.A. Ross and J. Cuvillier, discussing Ross' wishes to meet and view fusulinid collections housed at the Laboratoire de Micropaleontologie at the University of Paris; Cuvillier replies the French holiday occurs August-September, a period where the lab will be vacant. Cuvillier doubts a useful trip to Paris is possible, though a meeting with a few individuals at the Petroleum Institute of France (l'Institut Francais du Petrole) could be., 003152
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Four handwritten letters by C.A. Ross to four separate members of the Institut Francais du Petrole; Ross thanks Nicholas Grekoff for his showing Ross the laboratories and operations of the Franch Institute of Petroleum, showing interest and wishing success in Grekoff's studies; address information for Dr. Maurice Lys, accompanied by info on where Ross is staying in Paris and when; Ross requests a reprint of one of Dr. B. [du]Jekhowsky's papers; Ross giving thanks to Dr. Jacques Sigal, Chief stratigrapher of the Pureau at l'Institut Francais du Petrole., 003153
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960-1961 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and C.J. Stubblefield, informing Stubblefield of Ross' upcoming trip to London September 14-20, 1960, and his (and June R.P. Ross') hopes to view Paleozoic collections of fusulinids, smaller foraminifera and bryozoans in the Geological Museum; Stubblefield acknowledges having received papers sent by C.A. Ross, arriving January 1961., 003138
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960-1962 - Correspondence mostly between C.A. Ross and C.G. Adams, with one (initial) letter from F.C. Fraser (at the British Museum) to C.A. Ross acknowledging presence of foraminiferal collections of interest to C.A. Ross at the museum; substantial correspondence between C.G. Adams and C.A. Ross regarding the loan and return of several specimens and partial collection blocks (including receipt/invoice of one loan)--some of this correspondence is hand-written (where originally included with boxes of bulk sample/rock specimens or as letter drafts)., 003139
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960-1963 - Two letters between C.A. Ross and G.A. Cooper pertaining to Glass Mountains locality information, acknowledgement of collections housed at the Peabody Museum and invoice for shipment acknowledgment of bulk specimens [USNM Loan 229791] loaned to C.A. Ross by G.A. Cooper from the National Museum (Smithsonian); two later letters dated Sep. 1963 from F. Collier to C.A. Ross regarding review of USNM loan 229791 to C.A. Ross, and apology for having later located the missing specimens associated with loan 229791 at the Smithsonian; one duplicate list of G.A. Cooper USNM collection localities from the Glass Mountains; one small cutout of the Hess Canyon quadrangle labeled with USNM localities 706, 706f and 704v., 003097
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960-1963 - Typewritten correspondence between C.A. Ross and G.A. Cooper and F.J. Collier regarding the loaning and return of three slides of specimens [=USNM numbers 139210-139212] from Cooper's USNM collection localities in the Glass Mountains, West Texas; the earliest letter of the bunch, written by G.A. Cooper, has handwritten notes from C.A. Ross pertaining to missing USNM locality information detailed in IPAR.003098 (see Associations Tab)., 003099
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960-1963 - One typewritten letter from Ross to McAlester at the Peabody Museum detailing return of slides including various YPM numbers used by Ross in publication of his GSA Memoir 88 (Standard Wolfcampian Series); one handwritten letter draft, 3 pages of handwritten notes detailing published specimens and return of specimens to the Peabody February 15, 1962, and thick stock copies of YPM ledgers detailing published specimens used for publication into Ross' GSA Memoir 88., 003111
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1960-1964 - Correspondence (4 typed, 1 handwritten) letter between C.A. Ross and Henning and Fru Anna Horn af Rantzien of Sweden; Ross inquires of Horn af Rantzien's Charophyta collections at the Paleobotany Institute of the Museum of Natural History in Stockholm, and requests a meeting August 13 in Stockholm, to which Horn af Rantzien obliges; one of these typed letters, dated Feb 7 1964, is sent to Mrs. Horn af Rantzien by C.A. Ross giving thanks for having sent a paper on Charophytes and greeting card; one handwritten, undated letter from C.A. Ross to S.B. Manum expressing grief having learned of the death of Dr. Horn af Rantzien [Henning, presumedly], after having made arrangements for Dr. Horn and his family to visit the Ross' in Urbana, Illinois--Mrs. Horn had sent a letter to Ross indicating her husband had died in an accident in a quarry in France September 14 (no year given, but must have been after 1960)., 003149
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1961 - A letter from Edward Wilson inquiring whether Ross encountered Waagenophyllum texanum Heritch (1936, p.144; a rugose coral) and whether or not he has specimens in his collection. Wilson notes only one transverse slice through a corallite was used to definitively describe the species; he wants to make the species description more robust and/or revamp it., 003083
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1961-1965 - Letters sent to and from C.A. Ross to faculty in China (J. Sheng), S. Vietnam (Vien and Saurin) and Japan (Kanmera) regarding sent and received reprints to/from C.A. Ross and related parties. One letter (to Kanmera) was written to C.A. Ross August 2, 1961, one written by J.C. Sheng on February 15, 1965 and three written by C.A. Ross on April 6, 1965 to Sheng, Saurin and Vien., 002903
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1962 - Five letters exchanged between C.A. Ross and G.A. Cooper regarding fusulinid identifications made by C.A. Ross for specimens collected from many of G.A. Cooper's USNM Glass Mountains localities. The earliest letter of the chain, from C.A. Ross, includes a request for locality data for five of Cooper's USNM localities as well as inquiry on current status of Cooper's Glass Mountains brachiopod paper; one duplicate (typewritten) list of G.A. Cooper USNM collection localities with miscellaneous Penn/Perm collections from various wells (USA) and other localities (global); Letter drafts by C.A. Ross and 2 lists (one handwritten, one photocopied) of specimen identifications for G.A. Cooper's USNM collection localities., 003098
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1962 - Carl Dunbar sent a letter to G.A. Cooper asking about Cooper's fusulines; a copy of this letter was sent to C.A. Ross a month later by Dunbar who thought Ross might be interested in his letter to Cooper about Cooper's fusulines., 003105
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1962 - One letter from C.A. Ross to G.A. Cooper detailing submission of "Early Permian Fusulinids from Macusani, Southern Peru" to "Palaeontology" (British Association) based on material loaned to Ross by Charles G. Adams of the Zoology Dept. of the British Museum (Natural History)., 003107
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1962 - One letter from Carl Dunbar to Charles Ross sending updates on G.A. Cooper's brachiopod paper, detailing a request by Cooper through Dunbar (by proxy) to Ross to return thin sections associated with a large fusulinid collection loaned to Dunbar by Cooper years prior., 003109
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1962 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and W. Ziegler; Ziegler bears ill news of Wedekind, Staff and Schellwien's collections, which were ultimately regarded as "lost" after the Soviet Union occupied the former German province of Eastern Prussia and, along with it, the University of Konigsberg, where the collections were suspected to have been housed at the time of correspondence--the Soviets renamed the university Kaliningrad; Ross returns his thanks for the valuable information on these collections, and is relieved to hear of Ziegler's safe return to Germany., 003136
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1962-1968 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and a number of parties ("origination" listed in order after C.A. Ross from earliest to latest) discussing requests for reprints of papers referencing Penn/Perm strata or fusulinids, and giving praise towards Ross' quality of publications., 003080
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1963 - Correspondence containing one letter addressed to C.A. Ross, written by David J. Dubin; contains specimen photography from thin section, derived from the David Dubin Collections A-7 and C-7 (Earp Fm. Type Section), SE Arizona (Dubin's M.S. Thesis, University of Arizona)., 002777
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1963 - One letter from C.A. Ross to Dr. James Gilluly discussing fusulinids at the type section of the Colina Ls and the section overlying the Earp type section in SE Arizona., 002860
    - Correspondence. Charles A. Ross - 1963 - Correspondence between C.A. Ross and David Dubin discussing potential willingness of C.A. Ross to review fusulinid identifications, age determinations and taxonomy made by Dubin; C.A. Ross obliges, offering his support to Dubin., 003081